[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这就给我们带来了这个并发的概念。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: That brings us to this idea of concurrency.
并发意味着什么？
What does concurrency mean?
很多人认为并发意味着两件事情同时发生。
A lot of people think concurrent means two things happening at the same time.
再说一遍，这是其中一件事，如果你眯着眼睛看它，你可能会说，是的，也许
Again, it's one of those things if you squint at it you might say, yeah, maybe
它们有点像，但这里有一个重要的细微差别。
they're kinda like the same but there's an important nuance difference here.
顺便说一下，如果有人想反对我的特殊用法
And by the way, if somebody wants to object to my particular usage of
这些词，实际上有很多不同的意思。
the words, there's actually lots of different meanings for these words.
而且很难确定一件事，所以
And it's hard to nail down one particular thing, so
我试着在我自己对这些东西的使用中保持一致。
I'm trying to be is consistent within my own usage of these things.
但实际上，如果你去阅读维基百科的页面或其他文本，
But there's actually, if you go and read Wikipedia pages or other text on it,
你会发现在这些事情上有一系列不同的观点。
you'll find a whole range of different opinions on these things.
但我向你解释并发是什么而不是说
But my way of explaining to you what concurrency is rather than saying with
并行性两件事情发生在完全相同的时刻，我会描述
parallelism two things are happening at the exact same instant, I would describe
并发：在同一时间范围内发生的两个更高级别的任务。
concurrency as two higher level tasks happening within the same timeframe.
所以我们不是一瞬间，而是看一个时间框架。
So rather than an instant, we're going to look at a timeframe.
我们会说在这个时间框架内，
We're gonna say within this timeframe,
将会发生两个更高级别的操作。
two higher level operations are going to occur.
理解更高级别的项目或更高级别的操作的概念
To understand the notion of higher level items or higher level operations
发生时，我们还必须了解更高的层次，或者我可以称之为宏观的东西
occurring, we also have to understand that higher level, or what I might call macro
级别任务可以被拆分，或者被认为是被拆分成微观级别的任务。
level tasks can be broken up or thought of as being broken up into micro level tasks.
所以这里有一种可视化宏观和微观层面的方法，并且
So here's a way to visualize the macro level and the micro level, and
这些东西是怎么结合在一起的。
how these things might go together.
所以在左边我们有这个黄色的橙色任务，有一个宏观层面的任务。
So the left-hand side we have this yellow orange task, with a macro level task.
它被分成一个个数字，1，2，3，4。
Which is broken up into those individual numbers, 1, 2, 3, 4.
这将是微观层面的任务。
Which would be micro level tasks.
这些是我编造的条款，这些不是官方条款。
These are my made up terms, these aren't official terms.
而是宏观层面和微观层面的任务。
But macro level and micro level tasks.
然后，在右侧，我们有另一个宏观层面的任务，表示为
And then, on the right-hand side, we have another macro level task represented by
那个蓝绿色，它被分成三个部分，1，2，3。
that blue green color, and it's broken up into three pieces, 1, 2, 3.
现在，为了数学的易用性，我将假装和
Now, for the easiness of math I'm going to pretend and
假设这些微级任务中的每一个都需要整整一秒钟才能完成。
assume that each one of these micro level tasks takes one full second to complete.
所以这个整体系统完成所有的任务需要七秒钟，
So this overall system to do all of the tasks it's going to take seven seconds,
每个人都同意这一点吗？
does everybody agree with that?.
因为它是一个单线程系统。
Cuz it's a single threaded system.
现在，这可能发生在完全相同的时刻。
Now, that could happen at exactly the same moment.
因此，这些一秒的微级别任务必须以某种方式进行调度
So those one second micro level tasks are going to have to be scheduled in some way
所有七个人都完成了，这需要七秒钟。
that all seven of them finish and that's gonna take seven seconds.
让我们假设黄色的橙色代表Ajax请求，并且
Let's pretend that the yellow orange represents an Ajax request and
响应周期。
response cycle.
发出一个请求，我们得到一个响应，然后
Fire off a request we get a response back and
让我们假设蓝色代表我们在页面上滚动的卷轴
let's pretend that the blue represents a scroll that we scroll on the page and
它重新绘制了所有内容，因为我们滚动到了页面的新位置。
it repainted everything because we scrolled to a new location of the page.
这两个操作必须从根本上发生在同一线程上。
These two operations have to fundamentally happen on the same thread.
我们浏览器的整个用户界面都发生在同一个线程上，所以
The entire user interface of our browser is happening on the same thread so
我们的JavaScript，垃圾收集器，样式引擎，重画，一切，
our JavaScript, the garbage collector the style engine, the repaint, everything,
这一切都发生在一个线程上，这意味着我们不得不担心
it's all happening on one thread which means we kinda have to worry about
争用，如果你曾经在你的页面上有过动画，那就让它抖动吧。
contention and if you've ever had an animation on your page have jitter in it.
你知道为什么会这样吗？
You know why that happened?
因为此时您的CSS引擎在UI线程上发生了争用
Because something contended on the UI thread at that moment your CSS engine
试图达到你的风格你的布局引擎试图重新绘制页面。
was trying to your style your layout engine was trying to repaint the page.
这是一个60帧的第二种方式，它正在重绘你的页面。
It's a 60 frames a second way that it's repainting your page.
它试图做到这一点，但就在那个时候，还有别的东西在运行。
It tried to do that but at that exact moment something else was running.
所以我不得不多等一会儿
So I had to wait an extra moment and
这就是造成抖动的原因，单线程。
that's what created that jitter, single threaded.
所以如果我们有更高的水平，
So if we have these higher level,
我们希望同时发生的宏级任务。
macro level tasks that we want to happen concurrently.
我希望黄色和蓝色同时发生。
I want the yellow and the blue to happen at the same time.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，让我们假设他们没有。
Well, let's imagine they don't.
调度这个系统的一种方法，调度这个程序的一种方法是做所有的
One way of scheduling this system, one way of scheduling this program is to do all of
先是黄色，然后是所有的蓝色。
the yellow first and then all of the blue.
在我们的页面上会是什么样子？
What would that look like on our page?
暂时忽略这一秒的东西，它在我们的屏幕上会是什么样子
Ignoring the one second thing for a moment, what it would look like on our
页面看起来就像我单击按钮来发出Ajax请求，然后
page Is that it would look like I click the button to make an Ajax request and
当这种情况发生时，我试图滚动我的页面，但
while that was happening I tried to scroll my page but
在那发生的时候，所有的东西都被完全冻结了。
everything was completely frozen while that happened.
然后，在它完成之后，它有点跳回来，赶上了。
And then, after it finished then it sort of jumped back and caught up.
我把它称为同步XHR，同步Ajax。
Ways I precedent for that It's called synchronous XHR, synchronous Ajax.
在网络平台上犯下的最坏的恶行之一。
One of the worst evils perpetrated upon the web platforms.
糟糕的主意。
Terrible idea.
外面有很多人在哭泣，而且真的在抱怨
There are people out there that are crying and literally complaining
在标准列表上说，你怎么敢拿走我的同步XHR？
on standards list saying, how dare you take away my synchronous XHR?
它已经被弃用了
It's been deprecated and
从网络平台上删除，因为这是一个非常糟糕的主意。
removed from the web platform because it's a really bad idea.
这样安排是个糟糕的主意，不是因为
It's a terrible idea to schedule it that way isn't it because
即使整个系统仍然需要7秒
even though the overall system would still take seven seconds
调度这些微级任务的特定选择。
that particular choice of scheduling those micro level tasks.
会觉得效率很低有人同意吗
Would feel terribly inefficient does somebody agree with that
只是从用户体验的角度来看。
just from a user experience perspective.
另一方面，如果我们选择将这些东西交织在一起。
If on the other hand we chose to interleave these things together.
有一件事可能阻碍了
Where one thing might be blocking so
我们可以在一件事情被阻塞时做其他事情，然后它才能移动到
we can do something else while one thing is blocking before it can move on to
下一件事，如果我们选择以内在的离开方式安排这些事情，
the next thing, if we chose to schedule those things in an inner leaved fashion,
整个系统实际上可能仍然需要7秒。
the overall system might still in fact take seven seconds.
但是对表演的感觉是事情将会发生
But the perception of the performance is that things are gonna be happening
同时，真的更重要的是，我们应该说这些话
in parallel really more importantly we should be saying those things
同时发生。
are happening concurrently.
AJAX和请求和
The Ajax and request and
响应与重绘同时发生。
response is happening concurrently with the repainting.
即使在任何给定的时刻，这些微级任务中只有一个正在发生。
Even though at any given instant only one of those micro level tasks is occurring.
所以想象一下我那奇特的动画花了我大约两个小时
So just to visualize that my fancy animation took me about two hours to
直接进入Keynote，这里有一种方法可以将这些微观级别的任务调度到
get right in Keynote, here's a way of scheduling those micro level tasks onto
中间的单个线程称为事件循环。
that single thread in the middle called the event loop.
我不知道它为什么前进，中间的单线程称为事件循环
I don't know why it advance, the single thread in the middle called the event loop
这就是我们在JavaScript中所说的。
that's what we call it in JavaScript.
在任何给定的情况下，只做这些事情中的一件。
At any given instance only doing one of those things.
所以当你有一个AJAX请求返回并且
So when you have an Ajax request that comes back and
您需要触发Call以获得响应。
you need to fire the cal back for a response.
如果在那一刻有人已经在执行了。
If at that moment somebody is already executing.
没人可以插队。
Nobody gets to cut in line.
你的响应回调不会中断并说，
It's not like your response callback gets to interrupt and say,
我该跑了。
it's time for me to run.
你知道它是干什么的吗？
You know what it does?
它就像其他人一样，排在队伍的尽头。
It gets at the end of the line just like everybody else.
所以当垃圾收集器说，我需要收集一些垃圾。
So when the garbage collector says, I need to collect some garbage.
样式CSS重绘程序说，我需要重画页面。
And the style CSS repainter says, I need to repaint the page.
布局引擎说，我需要做一些工作。
And the layout engines says, I need to do some work.
以及JavaScript引擎，
And the JavaScript engine,
说我需要在他们中的每一个人中触发这个响应回调。
says I need to fire this response call back in every single one of them.
这是一个先到先发的发球，每个人都排在队伍的最后。
It's a first come first serve, everybody gets at the end of the line.
这就是事件循环的本质。
That is fundamentally what the event loop is.
这就是帮助您理清正在发生的事情的高级视图。
Such is the high level view to help you sort out what's going on.
这里的要点是，这项工作的日程安排并不总是
And the main point here is that the scheduling of this is not always
完全在我们的控制之下。
entirely within our control.
有时，是比赛条件决定了其中一种情况与另一种发生的情况。
Sometimes it's race conditions that choose one versus the other happening.
并不是所有这些都在发生，但是有很多必要的协调。
Not all that's happening, but there's an awful lot of coordination necessary.
有时是事情发生时的协调，
Sometimes it's the coordination of when things happen,
但通常情况下，它是对发生的事情的反应的协调。
but oftentimes it's the coordination of responses to things happening.
因为它并不总是很连续的，像这样做，并且
Cuz it's not always a very serial, like do this and, and
当完成后做这个，然后当那是一个问题的时候，通常它是很多的
when that's finished do this and then when that's an issue that oftentimes it's much
更复杂的是，嘿，并行地做这三件事。
more complex like hey go do these three things in parallel.
然后，当其中至少有两个完成后，你可以继续前进
And then, when at least two of them have finished you can move on and
做另一件事，然后当第三件事出现时，你可以
do this other thing and then when that third one comes along you can
在这里分支，然后做另一件事。
branch out here and do this other thing.
不久之后。
And before long.
这只是可能发生的事情的不同状态的疯狂的复杂树，而且
It's just crazy complex tree of different states of things that could happen, and
这就是我们必须在我们的程序中管理的复杂性。
it's that complexity that we have to manage in our programs.
正是这种复杂性要求我们有更好的模式
It's that complexity that begs for us to have better patterns for
并发管理。
concurrency management.
这就是异步编程，管理我们的并发性。
That's what asynchronous programming is, managing our concurrency.
所以这是一个动机
So that's a motivation for
你从哲学和概念的基础上为
you from a philosophical and conceptual basis of the motivation for
为什么我们会竭尽全力去写我们所做的程序。
why we go to the lengths that we do to try to write the programs that we do.
在这个工作坊里我要向你展示的一切都是可以
Everything that I'm gonna show you in this workshop is something that could
从根本上说，除了回调之外什么都不做，没有新的功能。
fundamentally be done with nothing but the callback with no new functionality.
但我们将看到，回调基本上不足以
But we're gonna see that the callbacks fundamentally are Insufficient for
表达更高和
expressing the higher and
我们现代JavaScript程序所做的更高级别的复杂性。
higher orders of complexity that our modern JavaScript programs are doing.
我们的现代JavaScript程序到处都是，
Our modern JavaScript programs are falling all over themselves,
因为我们需要这些高阶模式，而且
because we need these higher order patterns, and
我们没有足够的纪律来学习和实施它们。
we're not disciplined enough to learn them and implement them.
我们只是继续做我们一直在做的事情，因为它总是有效的，而且
We just keep doing the same thing we've always done, because it always worked, and
它总是有效的，而且总是有效的。
it always worked, and it always worked.
这是对JavaScript能力的新基线的战斗号召
This is a call to arms to say the new baseline of competency as a JavaScript
开发人员需要有一个更加复杂的战略和战术
developers is to have a much more sophisticated strategic and tactical
接近你的并发管理，你的异步编程。
approach to your concurrency management, to your asynchronous programming.